Guide to the Yale University Press Records, Promotional Material, and Memorabilia for The Chronicles of America and Chronicles of America Photoplays
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Yale University Press, records, promotional material, and memorabilia for The Chronicles of America and Chronicles of America Photoplays
1920-1971
RU 131
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
1
(3 boxes)
The records consist of promotional material, correspondence, lease and license agreements, project records and memorabilia documenting the publication of The Chronicles of America and Chronicles of America Photoplays by the Yale University Press.
Yale University Press
Arrangement
The collection is arranged by type of material.
General note
Forms part of Yale Record Group 34-B (YRG 34-B), Program and project records of the Yale University Press.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Scope and Contents
The records consist of promotional material, correspondence, lease and license agreements, project records and memorabilia documenting the publication of The Chronicles of America and Chronicles of America Photoplays by the Yale University Press.
Chronicles of America series; Publishers and publishing; University presses; Yale University Press
- Records, promotional material, and memorabilia, Circa 1925-1952; Accession 1994-A-141
  - Correspondence, brochures, teacher"s manual, 1926-1952 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Photographs, circa 1925 (Box 1, Folder 2 - 5)
- Records, 1920-1971; Accession 2013-A-087
  Conditions Governing Access
  The materials are open for research.
  - Lease and license agreement between Yale University Press and Picture Corp, 1920-1956 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence-George Parmly Day with F.E. Spaulding and others, 1924-1954 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Promotion materials, 1925-1968 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence-Tax returns and Class B stocks, 1940-1959 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Memorandum-history of the Chronicles of America Project by George Parmly Day, 1944 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence and promotional materials, 1944-1971 (Box 1, Folder 6-7)
  - Correspondence-George Parmly Day to Arthur Block and revised agreements, 1946-1962 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence-George Parmly Day and U.S. Publishers Association, 1952-1959 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Yale Community Service Foundation, 1954 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - National Film Board of Canada, 1959-1961 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Photoplays-analysis of research materials, 1959-1960 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence-film replacement, 1960-1962 (Box 2, Folder 13)